Guide to the James Ladd Delkin Papers, 1918-1954
Department of Special Collections
James Ladd Delkin Papers,
1918-1954
Special Collections M0647
Delkin, James Ladd.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Berthe Delkin, 1993.
Biography
Local printer who published mainly San Francisco and vicinity guides and histories.
Scope and Content
Examples of his books and pamphlets, as well as wood and metal printers blocks, original illustrations, and a bit of personal material.
Access Terms
Printing--California.; San Francisco (Calif.)--Description and travel.; San Francisco Bay Area (Calif.)--Description and travel.
Container List
- Series I: Personal Items
  - JLD's enlistment record and honorable discharge from the U.S.Army, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of honor from Stanford University for JLD's military service. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - JDL's Diploma of Graduation from Stanford University, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Printing ephemera, proofs, and monographs from press
  - United States copyright certificate for Around the World in San Francisco, issued to JLD, 1941. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Unfolded dust jacket for Voyage to California 1849. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertisement and reviews for Mear's Pacific Ocean Handbook, published by JLD. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Award from Rounce and Coffin Club, Los Angeles, ca. 1946. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Souvenir envelope from Flavor of San Francisco. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Announcement for Jean Burton's Katharine Felton and her Social Work in San Francisco, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Program for the San Francisco Bay Area Institute on Inter-American Affairs. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Around the World in San Francisco" - original prints. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Envelope of wood block prints for a calendar, perhaps "Around the World in San Francisco" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Unbound edition on colored paper of prints from "Around the World in San Francisco" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proof for work of prints by Pauline Vinson. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proofs for Hilltop Russians in San Francisco, Pictures by Pauline Vinson, Text by William Saroyan. Published by JLD, 1941. Includes also drawings, watercolors, woodcuts. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Almanach for Thirty-niners. Federal Writers Project of the Works Project Administration in the City of San Francisco.Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1938. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Benson, Rex. Parodies in Paradise. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1945. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chadwick Easy San Francisco Street Guide. San Francisco: James Ladd Delkin c/o Recorder Press, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chadwick San Francisco Street and Transportation Guide. San Francisco: James Ladd Delkin c/o Recorder Press, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chadwick San Francisco Street and Transportation Guide. James Ladd Delkin c/o Recorder Press, ca. 1954. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chadwick San Francisco Street and Transportation Guide. James Ladd Delkin c/o Recorder Press, 1952. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Delkin, James Ladd. Flavor of San Francisco, a guide to "The City." Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Delkin, James Ladd. Flavor of San Francisco, a guide to "The City." Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diary of a 49er. Chauncey L. Canfield, ed. California Centennial Classic edition. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1947. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dietruch, Dr. Voyage to California 1849 - the German Emigrants, or Frederick Wohlgemuth's Voyage to California. Transl. by Leopold Wray. Republished for the Calfornia Centennial Celebration, 1949. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1949. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hildebrand, Joel H. Lowdown on Higher Education. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Johnston, Oliver M. Measure of a Man. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1947. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Landels, Thomas Durley. Things New and Old. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mears, Eliot G. Pacific Ocean Handbook. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1944. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Monterey Peninsula. Writers Program of the Works Project Administration in Northern California. American Guide Series. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1941. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Monterey Peninsula. Writers Program of the Works Project, Administration in Northern California. American Guide Series. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Murray, Justin. Cable Car Daze in San Francisco. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1947. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Parker, Frank. Anatomy of the San Francisco Cable Car. with 16 full-page photographs and 33 drawings. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Watts, Alan W. Meaning of Happiness: the Quest for freedom of the Spirit in Modern Psychology and the Wisdom of the East. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1953. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Watts, Alan W. Zen. Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Joseph. World from San Francisco, a Great Circle Map, Azimuthal Equidistant Projection.Stanford University: James Ladd Delkin, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series III: Wood Blocks
  - Wood and metal printers blocks, including plates for Pacific Ocean Handbook, Alchemy title page and decorative border, amd Monterey Peninsula. (Othertype Small suitcase)
    Contents include 2 boxes of plates and 9 individual items.